<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lucydot</title>
    <link>https://lucydot.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Lucydot</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 13:47:56 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://lucydot.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 May 2017 13:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Lucy Whalley (My CV, ):
I am a PhD student researching the electronic structure of solar cell materials in the Walsh Materials Design group at Imperial College London. My research uses solid-state physics and supercomputers to investigate why particular materials can efficiently convert sunlight into electrical energy.
I am a qualified teacher, and I have taught mathematics in a variety of settings - prisons, primary schools and cafes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>research</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 May 2017 13:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/research/</guid>
      <description>My research is centred around a family of materials called the hybrid halide perovskites. These materials have become incredibly popular over the last decade as they can convert sunlight into electricity efficiently, and have the potential to form more flexible, lightweight and cheaper solar panels than those currently on the market. My research aims to understand the quantum physics underlying this material so that we can improve the efficiency of future devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>software</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/software/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 13:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/software/</guid>
      <description>I am a computational scientist and a significant part of my time is spent writing code. Some of this code helps me to submit and manage my calculations which run on various supercomputers (primarily Archer, the UK national supercomputer). The rest of the code I write is used to analyse and extract meaning from the output from these calculations (numbers &amp;ndash;&amp;gt; physics).
Python and Bash are my go-to languages. Like many scientists, I am a self-taught programmer and have had very little in the way of training.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>open_science</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/open/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 15:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/open/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Open&amp;rdquo; is a bit of a buzz-word at the moment: open source, open access, open data&amp;hellip; but openness is necessary for scientific progress and the focus on open science is long overdue. Open science leads to:
 efficient use of money and researcher time (less duplication) a more equal scientific community (as some scientists do not have the resources to go to conferences or pay for journal subscriptions) reproducible research (see Stodden et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>teaching</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/teaching/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 13:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/teaching/</guid>
      <description>I am a qualified teacher and hold a Post-Graduate Certificate in Education (PGCE) with a specialism in mathematics. Although most of my time and focus is now upon research, I&amp;rsquo;ve kept up my teaching practice via the Software Carpentry organisation. With support from other volunteer instructors around the world, I teach basic programming skills (version control using git, bash shell scripting and python) to researchers at Imperial College London and beyond.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>publications</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 12:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>My publication list can also be accessed via Google Scholar or Orcid.
Impact of non-parabolic electronic band structure on the optical and transport properties of photovoltaic materials Physical Review B Lucy D. Whalley, Jarvist M. Frost, Benjamin J. Morgan, Aron Walsh DOI: 10.1103/PhysRevB.99.085207 Download here 
 effmass: An effective mass package The Journal of Open Source Software Lucy D. Whalley DOI: 10.21105/joss.00797 Download here  Code here
H-center and V-center defects in hybrid halide perovskites ACS Energy Letters Lucy D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>talks</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/talks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 13:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/talks/</guid>
      <description>I like to talk about my work to a variety of audiences. If you&amp;rsquo;d like me to speak at your event, please email me at The slides for some of my talks can be found here.
Public talks and outreach
 My work as a materials scientist  Girls in Physics series, London (UK), April 2019
Saving the world with Quantum Mechanics  Gunmaker&amp;rsquo;s Arms, Birmingham (UK), July 2017
Renewable energy workshop St Saviour&amp;rsquo;s School, Bath (UK), March 2016 Video here</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>dotspace</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/dotspace/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 17:12:04 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/dotspace/</guid>
      <description>dotspace is a collaboration with the musician and visual artist Richard Scott, who is interested in how scientific concepts such as order, disorder and ergodicity manifest in visual art.
Richard&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;dotspace&amp;rdquo; pictures are inteference patterns, created by overlaying binary number sequences. These drawings are painstaking work which involve a lot of counting. When we first met, he was screening for new, interesting patterns by hand. I offered to write a programme to automate this screening step and allow Richard to generate trial pictures very quickly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>misc.</title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/miscellaneous/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2012 13:47:56 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/miscellaneous/</guid>
      <description>SDF 
I&amp;rsquo;ve played with the band SDF for over ten years. We met in a pub when I was doing my A-levels. I was sat with a friend and a magician came to our table. For this magic trick he would need two other people, and the two on the table to the left of us would do. We got talking, they were looking for a band member (any instrument would do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://lucydot.github.io/ssi_fellowship/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://lucydot.github.io/ssi_fellowship/</guid>
      <description>activities:
 Meeting with Jeremy to discuss options for  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>